Register of the Joseph Warren Stilwell papers 51001
Hoover Institution Archives
- China-Burma-India Command File, 1942-1945
  - File 172.
    - Minutes of the 134th Supreme Allied Command meeting, undated (Box-folder 33: 6)
    - Notes on a conference held at the headquarters of the Chinese army in India, 1944 July 25 (Box-folder 33: 7)
    - Notes on the Supreme Allied Command Conference, 1944 June 30 (Box-folder 33: 8)
    - Press interview of Joseph W. Stilwell by Kandy Ceylon, 1944 August 5 (Box-folder 33: 9)
  - File 173.
    - Intelligence report from John S. Service to the Assistant Chief of Staff, 1944 (Box-folder 33: 10)
      Concerning the attitude of General Ho Ying-chin toward American military help to China.
    - Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to Chih Hui Pu concerning rehabilitation camps, 1944 March 14 (Box-folder 33: 11)
    - Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to all Commanding Generals and Officers, Chinese Army in India, 1944 March 16 (Box-folder 33: 12)
      Concerning the payment of gratuities in case of death or disability.
    - Memorandum from John S. Service to Joseph W. Stilwell., 1944 May 6 (Box-folder 33: 13)
      Concerning a plan for benefit payments to families of Chinese soldiers killed in Burma, and concerning a project to bring American-Chinese technicians to China for service with the Chinese Army.
    - Progress reports from Robert C. Beilke to Ernest Easterbrook, 1944 April 30, July, and August 1 (Box-folder 33: 14)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 33: 15)
  - File 174. Incoming radio messages for Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 February (Box-folder 33: 16)
  - File 175. Incoming and outgoing radio messages of Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 October (Box-folder 33: 17)
  - File 176. Incoming radio messages for Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 August-September (Box-folder 33: 18)
  - File 177.
    - Draft of a radio message by Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 August 29 (Box-folder 33: 19)
    - Incoming radio messages for Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 August (Box-folder 33: 20)
  - File 178.
    - Draft of a radio message by Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 July 16 (Box-folder 33: 21)
    - Incoming radio messages for Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 July (Box-folder 33: 22)
  - File 179. Charts, inventories, and radio messages between George C. Marshall and Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 33: 23-24)
    Concerning the China Defense Supplies operations and the Chinese Emergency Air Transport program.
  - File 180. Charts showing supply shipments over the hump to Y-Force, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 33: 25)
  - File 181.
    - Book, entitled Chinese Military Tactics and Strategy, by Sun Tzu, edited by Dai-Ming Lee, undated (Box-folder 33: 26)
    - Issue of the New China Daily Press, 1944 September 22 (Box-folder 33: 27)
    - Printed copy of the Constitutional Party's memorandum to President Franklin D. Roosevelt, undated (Box-folder 33: 28)
  - File 182. Y-Force map and overlay, undated (Map-case folder 34)
  - File 183.
    - Historical reports, maps, memoranda, orders, and rosters concerning the Y-Force, 1944 (Box-folder 33: 29)
    - Map of the Changsha area, undated (Box-folder 33: 30)
    - Notes of Col. Wood on the Y-Force, undated (Box-folder 33: 31)
    - Report from Frank Dorn to the Adjutant General concerning the Y-Force historical report for 1943, 1944 (Box-folder 33: 32)
  - File 184.
    - Draft of a message from President Franklin D. Roosevelt to Chiang Kai-shek, undated (Box-folder 33: 33)
    - Memoranda from John P. Davies to Ambassador Clarence Gauss, 1943-1944
      - "Stilwell Mission,", 1943 March 9 (Box-folder 33: 34)
      - "Policy Conflicts Among the United Nations,", 1943 September 17 (Box-folder 33: 35)
      - "Anglo-American Cooperation in East Asia,", 1943 November 15 (Box-folder 33: 36)
      - "The China and Southeast Asia Theaters: Some Political Considerations,", 1943 November 22 (Box-folder 33: 37)
      - "Interview Regarding the Chinese Situation,", 1943 December 16 (Box-folder 33: 38)
      - Memorandum of conversations with Dr. Wang Chung-hui and Dr. Sun Fo concerning Chinese military prospects for 1944, 1943 December 16 and 18 (Box-folder 33: 39)
      - "Chiang Kai-shek and China,", 1943 December 31 (Box-folder 33: 40)
      - "Observers' Mission to North China,", 1944 January 15 (Box-folder 33: 41)
      - "Coordinated Attacks on Japan's Inner Zone,", 1944 January 16 (Box-folder 33: 42)
      - "British Attitude Towards Chinese Troops in Burma,", 1944 January 28 (Box-folder 33: 43)
      - "American Policy in Asia,", 1944 February 19 (Box-folder 33: 44)
      - "Fourth Army Military-Political Group in China,", 1944 June 28 (Box-folder 33: 45)
        3 pages
    - Memorandum of conversation between Harry Hopkins and John P. Davies, 1944 September 4 (Box-folder 33: 46)
    - Memorandum from John P. Davies to the Secretary of State, 1944 March 10 (Box-folder 33: 47)
    - Report no. 5 from John S. Service to the Commanding General concerning communist policy toward the Kuomintang, 1944 August 3 (Box-folder 33: 48)
  - File 185. Incoming and outgoing radio messages of Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 June-August (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - File 186. Incomimg and outgoing radio messages of Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 March-September (Box-folder 34: 2)
  - File 187. Memoranda between Joseph W. Stilwell and Chiang Kai-shek, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  - File 188. Maps of Imphal operations, undated (Box-folder 34: 4)
  - File 189. Radio message from Joseph W. Stilwell to Claire Lee Chennault concerning diversion of gasoline, 1944 October 17 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - File 190. Report on the Chinese Army Services of Supply, undated (Box-folder 34: 6)
    Includes charts and index.
  - File 191. Minutes and notes on the Sino-American Conference on Anakim operation, 1943 November (Box-folder 34: 7)
  - File 192.
    - Letter from Thomas G. Hearn to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 August 1 (Box-folder 34: 8)
    - Lists, notes, and chart concerning supply problems, 1944 September (Box-folder 34: 9)
    - Memorandum from Frank Dorn to Joseph W. Stilwell concerning supply plan for the Y-Force, 1944 August 30 (Box-folder 34: 10)
  - File 193.
    - Letter from Glen Edgerton to Daniel Sultan, 1944 September 12 (Box-folder 34: 11)
      Concerning the screening of British and Indian requirements.
    - Memorandum from R. F. Seedlock to the Chief of Staff, 1944 September 5 (Box-folder 34: 12)
      Concerning matters for Joseph W. Stilwell's attention.
  - File 194. Memorandum from George E. Stratemeyer to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 September 4 (Box-folder 34: 13)
    Concerning potential air tonnage over the hump.
  - File 195.
    - Letter from H. H. Arnold to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 September 6 (Box-folder 34: 14)
      Concerning the 14th Air Force plan for East China Defense and Y-Force support.
    - Memorandum from Claire Lee Chennault to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 November 9 (Box-folder 34: 15)
      Concerning air support for Y-Force.
    - Memorandum from Claire Lee Chennault to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 June 4 (Box-folder 34: 16)
      Concerning the plan for East China Defense.
  - File 196. Chart showing the schedule for airfield development, 1944 (Box-folder 34: 17)
  - File 197.
    - Memorandum from Francis Hill to Daniel Sultan, 1944 September 2 and 4 (Box-folder 34: 18)
      Concerning the shipment of Canadian supplies over the hump.
    - Memorandum from W. S. Brewster to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 September 6 (Box-folder 34: 19)
      Concerning the plan for distribution of rifles and machine guns.
  - File 198. Chart showing the battle order as of July 1, 1944 (Box-folder 34: 20)
  - File 199. Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to Chiang Kai-shek, 1943 November 11 (Box-folder 34: 21)
    Concerning his proposals for the coming Sextant Conference,
  - File 200. Memorandum from J. A. McNerney to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 September 4 (Box-folder 34: 22)
    Reporting on the condition of airfields, pipeline, railroad, and roads.
  - File 201. Memorandum from George C. Armstrong to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 July 13 (Box-folder 34: 23)
    Concerning the inspection of medical activities.
  - File 202. Tables of organization for the Chinese Infantry Division, 1943 November 1 (Box-folder 34: 24)
  - File 203.
    - Memorandum from Joseph K. Dickey to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 September 5 (Box-folder 34: 25)
      Concerning items of interest in an intelligence summary. Includes map showing disposition of Japanese troops in Hengyang area as of September 5, 1944.
    - Weekly intelligence report, no. 47, 1944 September 7 (Box-folder 34: 26)
  - File 204.
    - Letter from Frank Dorn to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 September 21 (Box-folder 34: 27)
      Letter concerning personnel.
    - Letter from Hayden L. Boatner to Joseph W. Stilwell transmitting medical reports, 1944 October 4 (Box-folder 34: 28)
    - Letter from Thomas T. Handy to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 August 30 (Box-folder 34: 29)
    - Letter from William E. Bergin to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 May (Box-folder 34: 30)
      Letter concerning awards.
    - Memorandum from Daniel Sultan to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 June 9 (Box-folder 34: 31)
      Relating to the demotion of an officer. Includes related materials.
    - Memorandum from Frank Dorn to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 September 22 (Box-folder 34: 32)
      Concerning brief estimate of Chinese commanders in the Chinese Expeditionary Force.
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 34: 33)
  - File 205. Memorandum to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 September (Box-folder 34: 34)
    Concerning replacement of officers and enlisted men.
  - File 206. Memorandum from Frank Dorn to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 November 11 (Box-folder 34: 35)
    Concerning the future training of Chinese troops.
  - File 207.
    - Letter and memoranda from Hayden L. Boatner to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 June (Box-folder 34: 36)
      Concerning the Myitkyina siege.
    - Maps, including of Myitkyina, undated (Box-folder 34: 37)
    - Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to General Ho Ying-chin, 1944 June 4 (Box-folder 34: 38)
      Concerning unauthorized assumption of command by the Commanding General of the 22nd Division.
    - Report on reduction of bunkers at Myitkyina, 1944 (Box-folder 34: 39)
    - Miscellany, 1943 (Box-folder 34: 40)
  - File 208. Maps of the Imphal operation, undated (Box-folder 34: 41)
    See also map case, folders 35 and 42.
  - File 209. Chinese battle order, Yunnan, 1944 September (Box-folder 34: 42)
    (not received by the Hoover Institution)
  - File 210.
    - Chart, map, and table concerning the 9th War Zone order of battle, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 34: 43)
    - Letter from Wei Li-huang to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 August 30 (Box-folder 34: 44)
    - Map of U.S. Army ground forces, 1945 January 10 (Box-folder 34: 45)
  - File 211.
    - Letters and memoranda between H. H. Arnold and Louis Mountbatten and between Joseph W. Stilwell and Louis Mountbatten, 1943 October-November (Box-folder 34: 46)
    - Radio messages from Claire Lee Chennault, Daniel Sultan, Douglas MacArthur, and others to Joseph W. Stilwell concerning the Manila raid, undated (Box-folder 34: 47)
  - File 212. Map and overlay of positions of the Chinese Expeditionary Force, 1943 October (Map-case folder 43)
  - File 213. Map and overlay showing Japanese forces in China, undated (Map-case folder 43)
  - File 214. Chinese map of China operations, 1943 November 11 (Map-case folder 43)
  - File 215.
    - Chart showing West Yunnan troops, undated (Box-folder 34: 48)
    - Letter from Louis Mountbatten to H. H. Arnold, 1943 November 1 (Box-folder 34: 49)
    - Letter from Louis Mountbatten to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 November 2 (Box-folder 34: 50)
    - Letter from Louis Mountbatten to H. H. Arnold, 1943 November 27 (Box-folder 34: 51)
    - Memorandum, undated (Box-folder 34: 52)
      Concerning organizational chart of integration of American and British Air Forces within Southeast Asia Command.
    - Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to the Southeast Asia Command, 1943 October 27 (Box-folder 34: 53)
    - Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to the Supreme Commander, 1943 October 27 (Box-folder 34: 54)
    - Memorandum from Frank Dorn, 1943 November 2 (Box-folder 34: 55)
    - Notes of the conferences held among Chiang Kai-shek, Shang Chen, Lin Wei, H. H. Arnold, Joseph W. Stilwell, and others, 1943 November (Box-folder 34: 56)
    - Report concerning the status of Chinese troops in Yunnan, undated (Box-folder 34: 57)
    - Writing by Joseph W. Stilwell, "Role of China in Defeat of Japan,", undated (Box-folder 34: 58)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 34: 59)
  - File 216.
    - Battle order, 1944 July 1 (Box-folder 34: 60)
    - Memorandum, 1944 August 28 (Box-folder 34: 61)
      Concerning the organization of the Allied land forces for operations in Burma.
    - Reports on the Supreme Allied Commander's visit to London, 1944 August 5-21 (Box-folder 34: 62)
    - Report of Emery J. Woodall to Joseph W. Stilwell concerning military courts, 1944 August 28 (Box-folder 34: 63)
    - Weekly summary of important information, Supreme Allied Command, Southeast Asia, 1944 August 19-26 (Box-folder 34: 64)
  - File 217.
    - Charts, lists, and memoranda, 1944 (Box-folder 35: 1)
      Concerning the China Defense Supplies Unit equipment quota and strength of Chinese combat units at Ramgarh.
    - Information and recommendations regarding the 5332nd U.S. Infantry Brigade, 1944 (Box-folder 35: 2)
    - Memoranda concerning the Chinese replacement situation, undated (Box-folder 35: 3)
    - Memoranda concerning the training of Y-Force cadres, 1944 (Box-folder 35: 4)
    - Memorandum from Dean Rusk to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 August 25 (Box-folder 35: 5)
    - Memorandum from Francis Hill to the Deputy Theater Commander, 1944 (Box-folder 35: 6)
      Relating to the status of organization, to the list of Chinese units, and to the Thirty Divisions plus 10% Program.
  - File 218. Incoming and outgoing radio messages of Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 July 6 - September 11 (Box-folder 35: 7)
  - File 219. Maps of situation in Burma, 1944 September 4 (Map-case folder 40)
  - File 220.
    - List of Chinese units approved for Lend-Lease supply, 1944 July 1 (Box-folder 35: 8)
    - Memorandum from Francis Hill to the Theater Commander, 1944 September 1 (Box-folder 35: 9)
      Concerning the Thirty Divisions Program.
    - Tables of organization for Chinese divisions, 1944 July 1 (Box-folder 35: 10)
  - File 221.
    - Charts and memoranda, undated (Box-folder 35: 11)
      Concerning operations in North Burma and the capture of Rangoon.
    - Incoming radio messages for Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 (Box-folder 35: 12)
    - Joint Planning Staff brief concerning "Lokan 19,", 1944 (Box-folder 35: 13)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 35: 14)
    - Memorandum from Daniel Sultan to George C. Marshall, 1944 May 6-7 (Box-folder 35: 15)
    - Memoranda from Dean Rusk to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 August 23 (Box-folder 35: 16)
      Concerning the Southeast Asia Command.
    - Message from Joseph W. Stilwell to Louis Mountbatten, 1944 August 14 (Box-folder 35: 17)
    - Miscellany, 1944 (Box-folder 35: 18)
  - File 222. Map of the Hengshan-Kweilin area (Box-folder 35: 19)
  - File 223.
    - Chart listing replacement training centers, undated (Box-folder 35: 20)
    - Compilation of Y-Force ordnance items received as of February 29, 1944 (Box-folder 35: 21)
    - Radio message from Thomas G. Hearn to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 August 1 (Box-folder 35: 22)
    - Revised table showing the first group of Chinese armies and divisions to be equipped with U.S. supplies, 1943 September (Box-folder 35: 23)
  - File 224. History of the Field Artillery Training Center, Yunnan, China, 1943 March 15 - 1944 October 16 (Box-folder 35: 24)
    Includes charts.
  - Miscellany, 1942 (Box-folder 35: 25)
    Includes a memorandum from John Magruder to Joseph W. Stilwell, regarding Chiang Kai-shek’s views on command in Burma, and fragment of a letter from Chiang Kai-shek.
- Original Diaries, 1900-1946
  Holograph notes, hardcover and spiral notebooks, and loose supplemental sheets used by Joseph W. Stilwell as diaries, arranged by numbers; may not always be in chronological order. See also: Career File/A-2 and A-26.
  - Black and white books
    - No. 1, 1941 December 11-1942 January 28 (Reel 1)
      Box 36, Folder 1
    - No. 2, 1942 February 8-1943 April 18
      Box 36, Folder 2
  - Black book, 1943 June – 1944 January 22
    Box 36, Folder 3
  - Daily diaries and notebooks
    - Unnumbered, 1900 (Box-folder 36: 4)
      Plebe Year. Winifred Stilwell transcription of Joseph Stilwell entries at end of diary number 4.
    - No. 1, 1900 July 28 – 1904 June 15 (Box-folder 36: 5)
      Cadet expense ledger.
    - No. 2, 1904 (Box-folder 36: 6)
    - No. 3, 1905 (Box-folder 36: 7)
    - No. 4, 1905-1906 (Box-folder 36: 8)
    - No. 5, 1907 June-July (Box-folder 36: 9)
      (Guatemala trip)
    - No. 6, 1907 July-August (Box-folder 36: 10)
    - No. 7, 1907 (Box-folder 36: 11)
    - No. 8, 1908 June-August (Box-folder 36: 12)
      (Mexico trip)
    - No. 9, 1909 June–August (Box-folder 36: 13)
    - No. 10, 1911 September-November (Box-folder 37: 1)
      (Japan)
    - No. 11, 1911 (Box-folder 37: 2)
      (illustrations)
    - No. 12, 1911 (Box-folder 37: 3)
    - No. 13, 1911 November-December (Box-folder 37: 4)
    - No. 14, 1912 (Box-folder 37: 5)
    - No. 15, 1914 June–July (Box-folder 37: 6)
      (Spain)
    - No. 16, 1914 August–September (Box-folder 37: 7)
    - No. 17, 1915 (Box-folder 37: 8)
    - No. 18, 1917 December 15 – 1918 February 10 (Box-folder 37: 9)
    - No. 19, 1918 February 6-May 31 (Box-folder 37: 10)
    - No. 20, 1918 June 1-September 25 (Box-folder 37: 11)
    - No. 21, 1918 September 26 – 1919 May 7 (Box-folder 37: 12)
    - No. 22, 1919 May 8-June 17 (Box-folder 37: 13)
    - No. 23, 1919 June 18-July 14 (Box-folder 37: 14)
    - No. 24, 1919 July 15 – 1922 March 23 (Box-folder 37: 15)
    - No. 25, 1921 (Box-folder 37: 16)
      (road building in Shansi)
    - No. 26, 1922 March-April (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - No. 27, 1922 April 17–September 13 (Box-folder 38: 2)
    - No. 28, 1922 September 13 – 1923 July 31 (Box-folder 38: 3)
    - No. 29, 1923-1929 (Box-folder 38: 4)
    - No. 30, 1927 May 24-June 18 (Box-folder 38: 5)
    - No. 31, 1927 September 5-24 (Box-folder 38: 6)
      (Korea and Japan)
    - No. 32, 1929 (Box-folder 38: 7)
    - No. 32X, 1933 May 30-November 5 (Box-folder 38: 8)
      ("Escape from Bondage")
    - Unnumbered, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 38: 9)
    - No. 33, 1936 (Box-folder 38: 10)
    - Unnumbered, 1937 June 18–28 (Box-folder 38: 11)
      (trip to Mongolia)
    - No. 34, 1937 November 23 – 1938 February 2 (Box-folder 38: 12)
    - No. 35, 1938 February 3-26 (Box-folder 38: 13)
    - No. 36, 1938 March 12-April 11 (Box-folder 38: 14)
      See no. 40 in box 41 for 1938 April 12-June 3.
    - No. 37, 1938 August 16-December 3 (Box-folder 38: 15)
    - No. 38, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 38: 16)
    - BOX 39 CLOSED.
      Access
      Only microfilm copies of the contents of Box 39 (1941-1944 diaries) may be used.
      - Unnumbered, 1941 December 7 – 1942 February 7 (Reel 2)
        Box 39, Folder 1
      - No. 43, 1943-1944
        Box 39, Folder 2. Includes data and notes.
      - No. 1, 1942 February 7-March 19 (Reel 3)
        Box 39, Folder 3
      - No. 2, 1942 March 19-April 17 (Reel 2)
        Box 39, Folder 4
      - No. 3, 1942 April 17-May 10
        Box 39, Folder 5
      - No. 4, 1942 May 10-July 19
        Box 39, Folder 6
      - No. 5, 1942 July 19-October 18
        Box 39, Folder 7
      - No. 6, 1942 October 19 – 1943 February 17
        Box 39, Folder 8
      - No. 7, 1943 February 18-June 15
        Box 39, Folder 9
      - No. 8, 1943 June 16-November 4
        Box 39, Folder 10
      - No. 9, 1943 November 5 – 1944 January 1
        Box 39, Folder 11
      - No. 10, 1944 January 20-March 20 (Reel 3)
        Box 39, Folder 12
      - No. 10½, 1944 March (Reel 2)
        Box 39, Folder 13
      - No. 11, 1944 March 30-May 31
        Box 39, Folder 14
      - No. 12, 1944 June 1-September 7
        Box 39, Folder 15
      - No. 13, 1944 September 8-December 5
        Box 39, Folder 16
    - No. 39, 1938 December 4 – 1939 January 18 (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - No. 40, 1938 April 12-June 3 (Box-folder 42: 2)
    - No. 41, 1939 May 1-July 3 (Box-folder 40: 3)
    - No. 42, undated (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - No. 44 (also no. 14), 1944 December 6 – 1945 April 20 (Box-folder 40: 5)
    - No. 45 (also no. 15), 1945 April 21–June 19 (Box-folder 40: 6)
    - No. 46, 1945 June 20-October 12 (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - No. 47, 1945 October 14 – 1946 March 10 (Box-folder 40: 8)
    - No. 48, 1945 June (Box-folder 40: 9)
      (trips to the Pacific – Okinawa and the Philippines)
    - No. 49, 1946 March 10-July 2 (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - No. 50, 1946 July 2-September 19 (Box-folder 40: 11)
- Transcripts of Diaries, 1900-1946
  History of the WWII diary transcripts (adapted from Hoover website):
  The World War II diaries were first transcribed several decades ago, when Stilwell's widow and a daughter-in-law, Bettye Stilwell, manually typed them.
  In 1998, Deborah Bunce, a cousin of John Easterbrook (grandson of Stilwell) started entering the manually typed transcriptions into a computer database.
  Several years later, Elena Danielson (then-director of the Hoover Library & Archives) came up with the idea of putting them on the Hoover Library & Archives website.
  With this goal in mind, John Easterbrook began proofing the computer database text against the original diaries. Deborah input the corrections Easterbrook noted, and Stefanie Diaz (a Hoover Archives staff member) rechecked the revised transcriptions.
  Janet Gardiner (an independent editor) compared these updated transcriptions with the original diaries, in order to make final corrections.
  Heather Wagner (audiovisual specialist, Hoover Archives) scanned Stilwell's maps of military maneuvers, and Polina Ilieva (technical specialist, Hoover Archives) pulled everything together and created a page on the Hoover Library & Archives website in 2005.
  Comments on the WWII diary transcripts by Janet Gardiner, editor (from Hoover website):
  "Every effort has been made to replicate accurately Stilwell's spelling and punctuation, superscripting and dash length, underlining and abbreviations—however unconventional or inconsistent in usage. Sometimes Stilwell deliberately used inventive spelling to poke fun at the accents of British military top brass and diplomats and of the Australians or West Africans. At other points, he wrote under such time pressure and preoccupation with the campaign that he inadvertently omitted terminal quotation marks, periods, and parentheses. Whatever the reason for the idiosyncrasies in the text, the transcribers have respected them. That said, this online presentation of the World War II diaries uses larger text pages than those in Stilwell's 2 ¾ x 4 ¾ inch spiral-bound notebooks. In addition, 1.5 spacing has replaced the single spacing of the original text, and entries are separated by line spaces, rather than by terminal line rules. Dates are in boldface and set off from the text with extra space, while preserving their original format. Stilwell's miscellaneous and undated jottings at the beginnings and ends of some of the volumes have been aggregated at the end of each year of entries, with their provenance indicated."
  Typescript transcripts of original diaries, arranged chronologically.
  - Large Black and white books, nos. 1 and 2, 1941 December 11 – 1942 January 28 and 1942 February 8 – 1943 April 18 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Black book, 1943 June 16 – 1944 June 22 (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - Daily diaries and notebooks (Reading room workstation)
    - 1900 (Plebe Year) (Box-folder 41: 3)